

Sirvan Doukchi SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Career Summary

Full-stack developer, with hands-on IT experience, passionate and motivated to actualise ideas all the way to implementing in browsers in a userfriendly and modern interface. I am committed to continually advancing my knowledge of relevant technologies including JavaScript, React JS/Native, TypeScript, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Node.JS and more.

I am also a footballer and very fond of my meticulously picked podcast shows!

Contact



Sydney, NSW



0406 471 171



SirvanSh@gmail.com

@sirvan-doukchi



www.Sirvan.Dev



https://github.com/SirvanD



Languages

- JavaScript
- · Node.js
- Ruby
- CSS/SCSS

Database/Cloud

- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Firebase
- AWS

Techs

- Docker
- · Jira Workflow
- Github Actions
- · Adobe Photoshop
- MS Azure
- CISCO CCNA

Frameworks/Libraries

- · React.js
- NextJS
- · Sinatra/PG
- Bootstrap 5 · Material UI
- Jest

Software Engineering Projects

Princes Theatre www



Front-End App where Star Wars fans can find an affordable option in between two streaming providers. Using an inconsistent API to retrieve information ad recall to receive a response. Components tested using Jest and API call mocked for integration test.

Tech Stack: JavaScript - React - SASS - JEST (React Testing Library)

Portfolio www



Professional portfolio designed with a mobile view first in mind and a minimalist look. UX and colour contrast principles are followed.

Tech Stack: React - NextJS - SASS - CSS3

BookShelf www



A community library Full-Stack application where users can signup/log in using own account or Gmail and donate/borrow books.

Tech Stack: React - NodeJS / Express - MongoDB for Database -Firebase Authentication - Material UI - Google Books API and REST API

Servo App www



Upon loading, given the location permission from user, this Full-Stack app marks the location of user, along with all petrol stations across Australia. Some other fun and useful facts have been also implemented.

Tech Stack: JavaScript - Node JS / Express - Google Maps API -Government provided DB - PostgreSQL - Bootstrap 5

Space Watch



Twitter-inspired Back-End app where users can register/login to share extraterrestrial images! Users can do CRUD actions, like images and view the most liked ones.

Tech Stack: Ruby/ Sinatra - Node JS - User Authentication - OMDBI API - CRUD actions - Deployed to Heroku

Tic Tac Toe www



The nostalgic Tic-Tac-Toe game is back with a minimalist 2 player user-friendly interface.

Tech Stack: JavaScript - DOM manipulation - Vanilla JavaScript -CSS / Bootstrap

Work Experience

Clayton UTZ Law Firm

Dec 2020- Sep 2021

IT Support Analyst

Active directory administration, Microsoft Azure user groups, forest and domain management, shared drives, and application of SCCM, RDP, Logmein, and Skype remote consoles for assisting remote clients.

Melbourne Institue of Technology Oct 2019 - Dec 2020

IT Support Officer

Liaise with internal staff and students over the phone and on-site utilising HEAT ticket management for level 1 and 2 services and escalation of level 3 and security concerns to infrastructure teams.





Sirvan Doukchi software engineer

Career Summary

Full-stack developer, with hands-on IT experience, passionate and self-motivated to actualise ideas all the way to implementing in browsers in a user-friendly and modern interface. I am committed to continually advancing my knowledge of relevant technologies including JavaScript, React JS/Native, TypeScript, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Node.JS and more.

I am also a footballer and very fond of my meticulously picked podcast shows!

Contact



Sydney, NSW



0406 471 171



SirvanSh@gmail.com



www.Sirvan.Dev



<u>@sirvan-doukchi</u>



https://github.com/SirvanD

Education

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly

Oct 2021 - March 2022

- Creating full-stack applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby, Express with Node.js, different databases, and Version Control (Git and GitHub)
- Integrated third-party APIs into websites and applications
- Working via remote correspondence and learning new methods of research, communication and collaboration

Masters in Information and Communication Technology University of Wollongong Jul 2016 - July 2018

Graduated with a distinction average with key subjects:
 Project and Change Management, Systems Integration,
 Information Systems and strategy, Strategic network design,
 IT security and Risk Management.

Internship and activities

IT Support Officer - Part-Time

University of Wollongong

Oct 2019- Jan 2020

- Provide effective level one support to the UOW community for all service requests, including incident diagnosis, troubleshooting, and accurate recording of calls received and resolution activities.
- Provide technical support for UOW standard desktop (Windows & Mac) environment.
- Participate in team meetings, and learning forums and share information with team members.

Information Technology Tutor - Part-Time

University of Wollongong

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

- Tutors students individually or in scheduled group study sessions to review principles of Networking and communication, solve problems, and review for tests.
- Maintains and updates confidential files and records, ensuring that ethical and legal guidelines are maintained.
- Researches and selects learning materials, textbooks, software, and equipment to facilitate tutoring; may design specific handouts, study, and related materials.
- Prepares and conducts tutorials, seminars and laboratory sessions, marks essays, assignments and examinations.

IT Technician Intern - Part-Time

CareSouth

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

- Observing and learning organizational skills, teamwork skills, and practising my academic knowledge in the industry level within a friendly, encouraging, and professional IT team.
- Undertaking IT issues reporting by employees through the ITS and ticket supporting system and attending maintenance.